<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.tcs.cleanux</id>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <name>Cleanux</name>
  <summary>A modern system cleaner and optimizer</summary>

  <developer id="com.tcs">
    <name>TechCraft Solutions</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>Cleanux is a powerful system cleaning utility designed to keep your Linux system running
      smoothly.</p>
    <p>Features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Cache cleaning</li>
      <li>Trash management</li>
      <li>Log file optimization</li>
      <li>Large file detection</li>
      <li>System service management</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.tcs.cleanux.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/rusnakdima/Cleanux/main/imgREADME/home.png</image>
      <caption>Dashboard view with system overview</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>System</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>cleaner</keyword>
    <keyword>optimizer</keyword>
    <keyword>system</keyword>
    <keyword>utility</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/rusnakdima/Cleanux</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/rusnakdima/Cleanux/issues</url>

  <provides>
    <binary>cleanux</binary>
  </provides>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.2.1" date="2026-03-30">
      <description>
        <p>Bug fix release for Flatpak builds on CI servers.</p>
        <p>Fixes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed Flatpak build failure on GitHub Actions by adding appstream dependency (appstream-compose was missing).</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-03-29">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.2.0 improves the Rust and Angular stacks, release metadata, and developer
          workflows.</p>
        <p>Rust backend:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Shared helpers for responses, filesystem scans, and privilege elevation; centralized
            AppError across listing flows.</li>
          <li>File preview moved into a dedicated service with base64 handling; cleaner service
            refactored for shared logic.</li>
          <li>Tauri commands now call CleanerService, DashboardService, and SystemService directly
            from routes (controller layer removed).</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Angular frontend:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Stricter typing (object-based table rows, trackBy, unknown instead of any) and clearer
            search filtering.</li>
          <li>GitHub release DTOs for AboutService; CleanerViewStore for tabs, search, and bulk clear
            with a slimmer CleanerView layout.</li>
          <li>Safer error handling in settings, system, and large-files views.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Packaging and tooling:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>npm scripts for lint (ng build) and CI (frontend build plus Rust test and clippy).</li>
          <li>Flatpak description updated to reference the route-based command layer.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-02-18">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release of Cleanux - A comprehensive system cleaning and optimization utility.</p>
        <p>Key features and improvements:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Comprehensive file cleaning service with parallel processing for cache, logs, and
            trash.</li>
          <li>System service management for controlling and monitoring background processes.</li>
          <li>Large file detection to help identify and manage disk space usage.</li>
          <li>Modern Angular v21 frontend with real-time scanning and tabbed interface.</li>
          <li>Modular backend architecture with Rust-based routes, services, and models.</li>
          <li>Dark mode support with theme persistence.</li>
          <li>Automated build system with Flatpak packaging and GitHub Actions integration.</li>
          <li>Optimized project structure following standardized naming conventions and modular
            design.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>
